Bodky, Erwin; Papers ger023
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Erwin Bodky Papers
1897-1958
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bodky, Erwin, 1896-1958
ger023
6 cubic ft.
The Bodky Papers include biographical materials, letters, musical programs, reviews, extensive manuscripts, arrangements, and printed material. Bodky studied piano with Ferrucio Busoni and composition with Richard Strauss and performed widely on harpsichord and piano. He left Germany and lived in the Netherlands, 1933–1938, and the United States from 1938 until his death. He was a professor of music at Brandeis University.
Biographical Sketch
Erwin Bodky was a keyboard performer and musicologist. He studied piano with Ferrucio Busoni and composition with Richard Strauss and performed widely on harpsichord and piano. He left Germany and lived in the Netherlands, 1933-1938, and the United States from 1938 until his death in 1958. He was a professor of music at Brandeis University. Erwin Bodky also served in the German Army in World War I. Additional biographical information is available from the Cambridge Society for Early Music website. Bodky was an organizing member of the society.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes biographical materials; letters of recommendation from Bruno Walter, Wilhelm Furtwängler, and others, 1922-1938; letters to his wife, 1915-1938, primarily as a German soldier in World War I; musical programs and reviews relating to his career as a keyboard performer and musicologist, 1908-1955; manuscripts relating to posthumously published book The Interpretation of Bach's Keyboard Works (Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 1960); extensive manuscripts of his own compositions and arrangements (instrumental, vocal, orchestral, and chamber music), 1906-1926; and printed material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arranged into 9 file series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in 1978 by Angelica B. Lee (Erwin Bodky's daughter).
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Musicologists.; Scores.; Correspondence.; Music; Bodky, Lilli.; Brandeis University.
- Biographical materials and correspondence, Undated; 1
  - Biographical material, education, employment, letters of recommendation, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Letters to his wife, 1915-1916 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Letters to his wife, 1916 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Letters to his wife, 1917 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 4-5)
  - Letters to his wife, 1918 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 6-7)
  - Letters to his wife, 1926 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Letters to his wife, 1933 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Letters to his wife, 1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 10-11)
  - Letters to his wife, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (Miscellaneous), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials and correspondence), Folder 13)
- Musical performances: programs, reviews, and letters of appreciation, 1908-1974; 2
  - Letters of appreciation for concerts and recitals, 1925-1952 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 14)
  - Letters of appreciation. TV Channel 2 "Roads to Mozart", 1955 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 15)
  - Programs and reviews, 1908-1933 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1914-1929 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 17)
  - Programs, 1915-1930 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 18)
  - Programs, 1930-1972 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1938-1955 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 20)
  - Programs, Undated (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 21)
  - Cambridge Society for Early Music, Undated (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 22-24)
    Scope and Contents
    Programs and clippings of reviews.
  - Clippings of reviews, 1931-1974 (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 25)
  - Clippings of reviews, Undated (Box 1 (2-Musical performances: programs, reviews, and lette), Folder 26)
- Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination paper; miscellaneous notes, Undated; 3
  (For publications, see Series VIII; for music manuscripts, see Series V).
  - "Execution of Bach's Keyboard Works on the Piano", Undated (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 27)
    (Miscellaneous music, notes, and typescripts).
  - "Das Handwerkszeug des Musikers und seine Handhabung", Undated; photocopy of typescript (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 28)
  - "Die Kunst des Klavier-Übens", Undated; typescript (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 29)
  - "The ornaments of the keyboard works of J. S. Bach", Undated; handwritten in pencil (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 30)
  - "Preface", Undated; two versions, carbons (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 31)
  - [Talk re harpsichord], Undated; handwritten in pencil (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 32)
  - "Werkverzeichnis zu Bodkys: Vortag alter Klaviermusik", Undated; carbon of typescript (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 33)
  - Examination paper with ten questions, Undated; handwritten, photocopy (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 34)
  - Notes (Miscellaneous), Undated; handwritten in pencil (Box 1 (3-Manuscripts of writings, lectures, examination pap), Folder 35)
- Miscellaneous items, Undated; 4
  - Falkenfeld. Die Musik der Schlachten, Undated (Box 1 (4-Miscellaneous items), Folder 36)
    (handwritten inscription to Bodky).
  - Found on Busoni's, Undated (Box 1 (4-Miscellaneous items), Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (4-Miscellaneous items), Folder 38)
- Music manuscripts by Bodky, Undated; 5
  - "Kalasins - Arie". Text aus der Berliner Illustrientern Zeitung, Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 1)
    Herm.Konzertsanger. Hermann Schey in Verchorung gewiducet von. 1 Ver-f fasser, 20. VII. 1922. Berlin. 7 p.
  - "Sonate für Klavier in einem. zweiteiligen Satz", 1921-1922; 30 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 2)
    (lacks ending).
  - "8 Canons in Tansform für Klavier", 22 [January] 1919 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 3)
  - "Klavier - Quintett A-Dur", 9 Oktober 1919; 52 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 4)
    Klavier-Quintett A Dur. Motto: "Rhythmus" For Violine I, Violine II, Bratsche, Cello, Klavier. Also, parts for Bratsche, violin cello, geige (violin) II.
  - "Spaziergang: I. Teil am See. II. Teil im Wald", 23 Juni. 1919 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 5)
    Klavier Konzert in C-dur. Op.6. No.2.
  - "2 groteske Tanze", 1919 June 22 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 6)
  - "Vier Lieder nach altdentschen". Texte für 4-8 strimmingen bhor a capella, 28. II. 1919; 16 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 7)
  - "Fruhlings Reigen der Ruhr Bazillen". Gent, Juni 1918 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 8)
  - "Canon in Ters und Gegenbewegung", 1916 March 16 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 9)
  - "Choralvorspiel: 'Wenn ich ihn nu habe für Orgel'", 1916 July 15 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 10)
  - Herzliebster Jesu für Orgel, 16. VII. [19]16 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 10)
  - "8 Canons in Form deutscher Taure für Klavier", 1916 March 24 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 11)
  - "4 Stimmige Fuge", 30 January 1916 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 12)
  - "Varianten uber ein altdentsches Lied für Klavier", 1916 September 10; 16 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 13)
  - "Sonate für 2 Klaviere in einem Satze". Berlin, D[en] 22. Mai 1915; 33 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 14)
  - "3 stimmige Fuge", 12. III. 1915 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 15)
  - "Praludium u. 3 stimmige Fuge", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 16)
    Fuga a 2 voci. 3 stimmige Fuge. 15. X. 1914. 4 stimmige Fuge eigenes Thema. 4 stimmige Fuge. Fine. D[en] 22 X. (19114. 4 stimmige Fuge. Thema von Herm. Prof. 3 uon. 24.X. 1914. Fine. 30.X. 1914. 4 stimmige Fuge. 4 stimmige Fuge. D[en] 20.XI. 1914. 4 stimmige Fuge. 2. Dez. 1914.
  - "Danse fantastique", 18. III. 1913; 8 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 17)
  - "Intermezzo", B[egonnen] D[en] 18. III. 1913 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 18)
  - "Poetische Tonbilder". No.1 stimmung, B[egonnen) D[en] 15. XII. 1912. Fine! D[en] 23. IV. 1913 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 19)
  - (no title), D[en] 29. VIII. 1913 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 20)
  - "Ballade". Erwin Bodky in Schierke i Harz, B[egonnen] D[en] 12. VII. 1912; 10 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 21)
  - Klavier Trio d-moll. "Trio in d-moll für Klavier, Violine und Cello" von Erwin Bodky, B[egonnen] 8. I. 1911. B[eendet] 6. I. 1912 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 22)
    Contents: "Klavierstimme" "Trio für Klavier Violine and Cello". B[egonnen] D[en] 8. I. 1911. Fine! D[en] 28. I. 1911. (p.14) "2. Satz". B[egonnen] 29. I. 1911. Fine! D[en] 6. I. 1911. (p.23) "3. Des Trio in d-moll für Klavier, Violine, und Cello". B[egonnen] 6. Vii. 1911. Fine! D(en] 8. VII. 1911. (p.27) "Trio in d-moll. Vierter Satz". B[egonnen) D[en] 10. 10. [19]11. D[en] 6. I. 1912. Inserted in music book Klavier Trio d-moll: "Lieder-Cyklus" von Pe Sturmbusch. D[en] 4. Mai. 1916. D[en] 7. Mai 1916. Miscellaneous orchestration. "Fuge a 5 uber den choral 0 heilger Geist kehr bei uns ein". 27. 11. 1919. "Niemals darfst du richtig sprechen diescs sei dern erstes. Ziel..." Gebet von Theodor Horner. [individual parts for scores in this music book]: "Trio für Klavier, Violine und Cello", "Violinstimme" (to p.l.), "Violine" (to p.23), "Cellostimme" (to. p.1, p.23).
  - "Violinsonate & Dur", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 23)
    Contents: "Sonate für Violine und Klavier". B[egonnen) D[en] 2. XI. 1911. 21. XI. 1911. "Violinsonate 2. ter Satz". B[egonnen] 10 XII. Fine! 11 VI 1911. "Dritter Satz der Violin sonate in a-Dur". B[egonnen) D[en] 1 VIII 1911. Fine! D[en] 13. VIII. 1911. "Violinsonata A Dur - Finale". B[eended] 17. 1. 1912. B[egonnen) 19. II. 1912. Fine! D[en] 5. IV. 1912. "Sonate für Violine und Klavier". 22. V. 1911. "Dritter Satz der Violinsonata A. Dur". Fine. 4. VIII. 1911. Ende. 5. IV 1912.
  - "Erlebuis", D[en] 18. III. 1911. D[en] 20. III. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 24)
  - "Erzahlung. No.5", B[egonnen] D[en] 14. VII. 1911. Fine. D[en] 11. VIII. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 25)
  - "Erzahlung. No.6", B[egonnen] 27. VII. 1911. Fine. D[en] 29. VII. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 26)
    (Erzahlung) No.2 in undated materials.).
  - "Intermezzo", 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 27)
  - "Poetische Tonbilder No.2", B[egonnen) D[en] 3. XII. 1911. D(en] 23. XII. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 28)
  - "Rhapsodie", D[en] 1. IV. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 29)
  - "2. Satz Der Sonate in Cis-molle", B[egonnen] D[en] 2. X. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 30)
  - "Stimmung", D[en] 3. IV. 1911. Fine! D[en] 4. IV. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 31)
  - "Unvollendete Sonate für Klavier zu Handen", Begonnen 7. IV. 1911, Beendet 26. IV. 1911 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 32)
  - "Klavierstuck". Op. 36, B[egonnen] D[en] 24. XI. 1910. Fine, D[en] 15. XII. 1910 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 33)
  - "Ballade. Op. 33", B[egonnen] D[en] 2. V. 1910. Fine! 4. V. 1910 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 34)
  - "Schilflieder No.2", B[egonnen] D[en] 18. XI [19]09. Fine. 18 XI. [19]09 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 35)
  - "So regnet es sich langsam ein", D[en] 6. XI. 1910. Fine! D[en] 6 XI. [19]10 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 36)
  - "Volkslied. Musik von Erwin Bodky. Op. 27", B[egonnen] 3. Dez. Fine. 3. Dez. 1909 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 37)
  - "Sonata. Op. 5. 3. 11", B[egonnen] 5. Mai. 1908 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 38)
  - "Sonate", 1906 (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 39)
  - "Cadence", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 40)
  - "Canon in Quarte", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 41)
  - "Duo serioso, I", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 42)
    [duet--score for piano]. 29 p., xi.
    [duet--score for the accompanying instrument] 8 p. (2 lines missing).
  - "Erzahlung. No.2", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 43)
  - "Fuga a 4", Undated; 6 pages (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 44)
  - "Intermezzo", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 45)
  - "Introduction und Adagio für Klavier und Orchester", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 46)
    [Untitled. Score for solo instrument and orchestra].
  - "Introduction und Adagio für Klavier und Orchester", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 47)
    Scored for 3 Flüten, 3 Oboen, 3 blannetten, 3 Fagotte, Horner in F, 3 Trumpeten in G, 3 Posaunen, Basstuba, 3 Pauken, gr. Trommel, Triangel, Becken, Tam Tam, Harpe, Violinen, Bratochen, bell, chabffsse (?), Klavier. undated.
  - "Mixer a Barmaid", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 48)
  - "Quartetto per due Violini, Viola et Violoncello. 'Motto: Though music, oft hath such a charm, To make bad good and good provoke to harm'", Undated (Box 2 (5-Music manuscripts by Bodky), Folder 49)
    Contents: "Quartetto per due, Violini, Viola, et Violoncello in fa minor".
    Scores (4) for individual parts of above work. Scores have title: "String quartet in fa-minor".
- Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky, Undated; 6
  Composers and authors whose works are included are:.
  Danthendey, Max (11).
  Dehmel, Richard (14, 23).
  Eichendorff (22).
  Flaischlen, Casar (12).
  Furinger, Peter (29).
  Goethe, J. W. (20, 24).
  Grief, Martin (13, 17).
  Halbmann, Paul (16).
  Hebel, Friedrich (31).
  Heine, Heinrich (18).
  Hesse, Herman (15).
  Kurz, Isolde (30).
  Lenau (21, 25).
  Morgenstern, Christian (8, 9, 26).
  Rhesa (22).
  Schwab, Gustav (19).
  Storm, Theod. (10).
  Sturmbusch, Peter (28).
  Uhland, Ludwig (27).
  Von Brabant, Herzag Johann (29).
  - "Sinfouisches Spiel für Kammerorchester", Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 1)
  - Sonate für Zwei Klaviere in einem. Satze", Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 2)
  - Spitzenhoschen. "Warum. sich so Keusch Genehmen...", Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 3)
  - "Streichquartett in f-moll" (score), Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 4)
    "Streichquartett in f-moll" 1 Geige, 20 p.
    "Streichquartett in f-moll" 2 Geige, 20 p.
    "Streichquartett in f-moll" Violoncello, 19 p.
    "Streichquartett in f-moll" Bratische.
  - 3 Klavierstucke (fragment), Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 5)
  - "Wenn am Abend frisch und labend...", Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 6a)
  - Individual parts of Fragments of composition, R-T, "Adagio" for lst violin, Violin 1, 2nd violin, Violin II, Viole, Violoncello, Oboe 1, Oboe II, Bassoon, Double Bass, French Horn I, French Horn II in E, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 6b)
  - Music manuscripts (Miscellaneous), Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 7)
  - "O Schweigen komm" von Christian Morgenstern für Alt und Orchester. Molle (Schweden), 16. August. 1926 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 8)
  - "Voglein Schivermut" von Christian Morgenstern für Gesang und Klavier. Molle (Schweden), 29. VII. [19]26 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 9)
  - "Über die Heide von Theod Storm", B[egonnen] 4. VI. 1914 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 10)
  - "Kein Abend werden will von Max Danthendey", B[egonnen] D[en] 3. IV. 1911. Fine. D[en] 2. I. 1912 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 11)
  - "Altes Lind von Casar Flaischlen", B[egonnen] D[en] 8. XII. 1911. Fine! D[en] 12. XII. 1911 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 12)
  - "Fremd in der Heimat von Greif in Musik gesetzt", B[egonnen] D[en] 8. 11. [19]10. Fine, 8. II. [19]10 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 13)
  - "Helle Nacht Paul Verlaine" von Richard Dehmel Op. 32, B[egonnen] D[en] 6. IV. 1910. Fine! D[en] 7. IV. 1910 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 14)
  - "Im Nebel von Herman Hesse", B[egonnen] D[en] 11. XI. 1910. Fine. D[en] 13. XI. 1910; 4 pages (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 15)
  - "Lied der Armen von Paul Halbmann". Op. 35, Fine. D[en] 1. IX. 1910; 2 copies (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 16)
  - "Schattenleben von Martin Greif" Op. 32 No. 2, B[egonnen] D[en] 20. IV. 1910. Fine. D[en] 2. V. 1910 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 17)
  - "Childe Harold". Heinrich Heine, B[egonnen] D[en] 17. VI. [19]09. Fine. 11 M IV. 1909 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 18)
  - "Das Gewitter" von Gustav Schwab. Op. 1 No. 1, 5. XII. 1909 (?or 04) (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 19)
  - "Requiem" von Goethe. Für Soli, Chor und Orchester, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 20)
    "For his father's birthday on 5. V. 1909".
  - "Der trube Wanderer" von Lenau. Op. 26, Fine. 19. XII. 1909 (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 21)
  - "Verschiedene Gedichte" von Eichendorff. Komp. von Erwin Bodky, B[egonnen] D[en] 14. XII. 1908. Fine. Beendet 20. XII. 1908. (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 22)
    Gervidmet: F. Bodky ad 8 September 1908.
    Contents: No. 1. "Fruche". No. 2. "Adler". No. 3. "Die Lerche".
  - "Der Vater an seinen sohn der ins Feld zieht" (Litavisch) von Rhesa. Op. 19 No. 5, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 22)
  - "Aufblick" von Richard Dehmel, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 23)
  - "Die Bekehrte" von J. W. Goethe, Undated; 3 pages (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 24)
  - "Fruhlings blick" von Lenau, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 25)
  - "Inmitten der grossen Stadt" von Christian Morgenstern. Tenor or Solo mit bhor, Undated; 17 pages (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 26)
  - "Das Tal" von Ludwig Uhland, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 27)
  - "3 Lieder für tiefe Stimme" von Peter Sturmbusch, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 28)
    Contents: No. 1. "Irgendwo drauss in der Welt", "Auf der Heide hockt, der Tod", "0 Mutter du Maria". undated.
  - "Vier Lieder nach altdentschen" Texten für 4-8 Stimmigen chor a capella, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 29)
    Contents: No. 1. "Ich klag Der, "lieber herre gott von Peter Furinger (1300) für 8 stimmigen ohor. [19]13? No.2 "Eines Maienmorgens schon" von Herzag Johann von Brabant. 7 stimmig. No. III. "Der schwere Traum". 4 stimmig. No. 4. "Ein Musikus wollt frolich wein". 4 stimmig.
  - "Wegwarte" von Isolde Kurz, Undated; 5 pages (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 30)
  - "Weihe der Nacht" von Friedrich Hebel, Undated (Box 3 (6-Music of others, adapted or orchestrated by Bodky), Folder 31)
- Music by others, Undated; 7
  - Die sieben Worte des Erlösers am Kreuz, Undated; photocopy (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 32)
  - Mozart, W. A. "Adagio für Harmonika Köch. Verz. No. 356, Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 33)
  - Mozart, W. A. "Maurerische Trauermusik", Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 34)
    für 2 Violinen, Viola, Bass, 2 Oboen, Clarinette, Bassethorn, Contrafagott und 2 Waldhorner (oder 2 Bassethorner). Köch.
    Verz. No. 477.
  - Bach, J. S. [Photocopy of Chorus], Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 35)
  - Bach J. S. "Praeludium 1-XXIV, Fuga, 1-XXIV", Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 36)
    [Inserted are 2 programs of performances in which this music was used (March 8, 1943; December 7th, 1943). Also interpretations of "Praeludium VII and Fuga XX".
  - Bach, J. S. Clavierwerke. Erster Band, Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 37)
    Contents: Fünfzehn Inventionen und fünfzehn Symponierf", "Das Italienisch Concert", "Toccata in Fis-moll", "Toccata in C-moll", "Toccata in D-moll", "Toccata in D-dur"(Fantasie und Fuge), "Fantasie und Fuge in A-moll" "Fuga, Fantasic in C-moll", "Chromatische Fantasie und Fuge". Leipzig: Steingraber Verlag, 1880.
  - Bach, J. S. "Clavierwerke". Siebenter Band. Vermischte Werke. Leipzig: Steingraber Verlag, 1888 (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 38)
  - Bach, J. S. "Clavierwerke". Vierter Band, Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 39)
    Contents: "Vier Duette in E-moll, F-dur, G-dur, A-moll" "Aria mit 30 Veranderungen, genannt, die Goldbergschen Variationen, in G-dur", "Sonate A-moll", "Sonate in C-Dur", "Sonate in D-moll", "Toccata in G-Dur", Toccata in E-moll", "Toccata in G-moll" Hannover, Steingraber Verlag, 1883(?).
  - [unidentified music], Undated (Box 3 (7-Music by others), Folder 40-46)
- Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used by Bodky, Undated; 8
  Some contain publications of his writings.
  - Books and pamphlets, Undated; 8.1
    - Arbatsky, Yury.Beatin the Tarpan in the Central Balkans, 1953 (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 1)
    - Bach, Joh. Seb.Kirchen-Kantaten, Undated (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 2)
      I von Ostern bis Pfingsten.
      II von Trimtatis bis 7. Sountag nach Trimtatis.
      III vom 8. Sountag bis Michadis.
      IV Ende des Kirchen jahres.
      V 1. Sountag im Advent bis Epiphanias 1947.
      Bach, Joh. Seb. Die Zweistimmigen Inventionen und die 15 Dreistimmigen Sinfonien, Urtext-ausgabe Revisionsbericht von Ludwig Landshoff. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, 1933.
    - Friedlaender, Max.Chorschule nach Stockhausens Methode. Zweit Auflage. Leipzig: C. F. Peters, [1909] (Box 4 (8-Books, pamphlets, periodicals, and offprints used ), Folder 3a)